# **DIEGO COSTA**

Tel: +598-98-823-886 Linkedin: link Email: diecoscai@gmail.com Addr: Montevideo, Uruguay

## **ABOUT ME**

I'm Diego, a 31-year-old computer enthusiast currently pursuing a degree in Programmer Analyst at ORT, with an intermediate title in Web Programming. I'm a committed and skilled professional who collaborates effectively in teams, offering innovative solutions. Proactive and dedicated to continuous personal and professional growth, I'm always seeking new challenges to enhance my knowledge and explore emerging technologies.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Freelancer

## Feb 2024 - Act

- Development of Front-End features using Angular.
- Development of Back-End features using Node.js
- Requirements gathering with client
- Custom development and theme modifications in Shopify.
- Website creation and management using WordPress.
- Requirements gathering with clients.

# Entravision Jun 2018 – Dic 2023 Advertising Operator

- Provided support and training on company platforms to ensure client satisfaction.
- Developed and optimized Spotify ad campaigns using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.
- Performed hotfixes on a DSP platform using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Conducted data gathering and applied Scrum methodologies for project efficiency.
- Acted as Scrum Master, facilitating agile processes and team collaboration.

# Multiline August 2017 – June 2018 Back-office Operator

- Provided customer support via phone.
- Handled documents and controls in the banking system.
- Managed client documentation for loan applications.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **ORT University**

### 2022-Present

## **Programmer analyst**

- C# (.NET), MVC, Web.api
- OOP (Object-Oriented Programming)
- JavaScript, React, Redux
- SQL/DDL (Data Definition Language)
- UML (Unified Modeling Language)
- Web Development
- Algorithms and data structure

# Jóvenes a Programar Web Development

Jun 2021-Dec 2021

- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap

## **SKILLS**

- JavaScript, Java
- HTML, CSS
- React, Ionic
- AWS, IIS, Azure
- Responsive web design
- SQL
- Problem analysis and resolution
- Upper Intermediate English (B2)

#### **REFERENCES**

Juan Pablo Florentin
 CTO - Growth Digital

Tel: +598 98 611 642

Email: juanpablo200285@gmail.com

Emanuel LaportaFull Stack Developer - Entravision

Tel: +598 98 567 684

Email: elaporta.s@gmail.com